孩子们 世上没有比
Kids, there's nothing more wonderful
冬天中的纽约更美好的景观了
than New York City in the winter...
除了透过你公寓的窗子
except the view of New York City in the winter
看到的冬天中的纽约的景致
through your apartment window.
2006年的冬天 马修 莉莉 罗宾和我
In the winter of 2006, Marshall, Lily, Robin and I
我们一直处在恋人冬眠状态
were all deep in couple hibernation mode.
无奈只剩下巴尼叔叔孤零零一人
Sadly, this left Uncle Barney out in the cold.
听好了   通宵狂欢
Okay. All-night rave,
在纽瓦克一家废弃的轮胎厂 (Newark:纽瓦克,美国俄亥俄州中部的城市)
abandoned tire factory in Newark.
我们都被邀请了 谁想去?
We're on the list. Who's in?
- 不去 - 不去
- Nope. - No.
私人飞机 蒂特伯诺机场 空中跳伞 谁去?
Private jet. Teeterboro Airport, skinny-skydiving. Who's in?
- 不去 - 不去 谢谢
- Nope. - No, thanks.
楼下喝杯啤酒 走15秒就到 谁去?
One beer. Bar, downstairs, 15 second walk. Who's in?
小点声... 莉莉睡觉觉了   拜!
Shh... Lily went sleepy-bye.
没有人愿意陪巴尼玩 他只能自己做自己的托
It got so bad, Barney tried to be his own wingman.
你想不想认识我?
Hi. Have you met me?
最后 他带来了援军
Finally, he decided to bring in reinforcements.
- 不去 - 不去
- No. - No.
我保准你们想去 知道问什么吗?
Yes. And do you know why?
抓抓你们的褥疮  爷爷奶奶们
Hang on to your bedsores, grandparents from Willy Wonka,
猜猜现在谁要到这里来
because guess who's on his way up to this apartment right now?
我的... 等等...
My... wait for it...
兄弟...詹姆士 你们什么反应?
brother, James. React.
- 咳! - 咳!
- Hey! - Hey!
- 你有兄弟? - 当然!
- You have a brother? - Yeah.
他人棒极了  长相也酷毙了
He's the "awesome-est," most best "looking-est," greatest guy ever.
他和巴尼一个样
He's exactly like Barney.
没错
That's what I just said.
巴尼和他的兄弟不是完全一样的
Well, Barney and his brother aren't exactly alike.
詹姆士是个同性恋
James is gay.
真的? 打死我也不会想猜出
Really? I never in a million years
你会有个同性恋兄弟?太好了!
would I picture you with a gay brother, that's awesome.
我就是想提醒你一下
Yeah. I just wanted you to have a heads up,
见到他的时候 你就不会过度惊讶
so you don't act all surprised when he gets here.
他来了
Here he is.
纽约的兄弟们 你们好吗?
What up, New York.
谢谢你的提醒
Thanks for the heads up.
本字幕由YYeTs美剧字幕组原创翻译制作
仅供学习交流之用 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
欢迎访问YYeTs美剧论坛进行交流 www.YYETS.com
老爸老妈的浪漫史
第二季 第十集
翻译：     ljw1911    校对：     紫苑
后期：     oliver0951      字幕监制：  叶煦
为什么从来没有人告诉 过我巴尼有一个黑人同性恋兄弟?
How in God's name did it never come up that Barney has a gay, black brother?
他是黑人?
Is he black?
我想我这人只注重人的内在美
I guess I'm the kind of person that focuses on who people are on the inside
而不是他们皮肤的颜色
rather than the color of their skin.
跟你开玩笑的 我只想让你吃惊一下
I'm kidding, I just wanted to see your face.
嗯对  我们又决定结婚了
Yeah, so now the wedding's back on.
不说这个了  詹姆士 你过得怎么样?
Anyway, James, how have you been?
好极了!
Awesome, as per "yoozh."
我刚玩完裸体跳伞  传奇一般!
I just went skinny-skydiving. Legendary.
我的激光游戏组刚打入地区决赛 (laser tag：一种激光枪游戏 )
And my laser tag team, just made it to regional finals.
比传奇更加传奇!
"Legendarier."
现在你们一定注意到我的西服了
And by now you've noticed the suit--
来来 摸摸
go 'head, touch it.
皮尔特洛・德拉卡拉　亲手制造
Handcrafted by Pietro Dellacamera,
他是米兰著名的101岁的裁缝
Milan's famous 101-year-old tailor
在缝完这件西服的最后一针之后
who upon completing the very last stitch
就死掉了
in this suit dropped dead,
太讽刺了  因为我穿着 这件西服的帅样也会让他死掉
which is ironic because that is how gorgeous I look in it.
来
C'mon.
支持一下
Gimme five.
支持一下  又流行了?
Is "gimme five" back?
我今天早晨在我博客里宣布的
Oh, yeah. I put it in my blog this morning.
伙计们 "gimme five" 又流行了!
Guys, "gimme five" is back!
詹姆士 这是我的女朋友罗宾
Oh, James, this is my girlfriend, Robin.
- 真荣幸认识你 - 我也是
- Hey. It's so nice to meet you. - You, too.
我要问一下  你们俩人的 肤色为什么不一样?
So, I have to ask, there's a story here.
拜托
Please.
这些年来巴尼和詹姆士 从他们的妈妈那里
The truth is, Barney and James got a lot of...
得到了许多不同的解释
different explanations from their mom over the years.
孩子 你们看起来有区别
Well, boys, you look different
是因为在我怀你的时候
because when I was pregnant with you,
我只吃香草冰激凌
I only ate vanilla ice cream.
当我怀你的时候
And when I was pregnant with you,
你能猜出我吃的是什么冰激凌?
can you guess what kind of ice cream I ate?
- 咖啡的? - 不是的 詹姆士
- Coffee? - No, James,
我吃的是巧克力冰淇凌
I ate chocolate ice cream.
但是我在怀你们俩的时候 确实喝了很多咖啡
But  I did drink tons of coffee when I was pregnant with both of you.
没有咖啡怎么能抽烟
Can't smoke without my coffee.
我不知道 这就是 那种让人搞不清的事
I don't know, boys, I guess it's just one of those things.
别再问我了!
Stop asking me!
你们知道你们是什么吗? 你们是两个小种族歧视者!
You know what you two are? You're little racists!
你们两个今晚想做点什么?
So what are you guys gonna do tonight?
我告诉你詹姆士今晚要做什么
I'll tell you what James is gonna do.
他要做被你忽视的事情
He's gonna do the job you've been neglecting.
就和往常一样 他会做得比你更好
And, as always, he'll do it a lot better than you ever did.
泰德...
Ted...
詹姆斯现在是我的托
James is my wingman now.
好吧
Okay.
上次詹姆士来的时候 巴尼被抽了一次巴掌
Last time James was in town, Barney got slapped once,
和别人上了两次床……
lucky twice, and...
你最后睡在了谁的浴缸里?
whose penthouse hot tub did you end up in?
公众人物 我们要为他保密
Ah, public figure, confidentiality agreement.
但我可以说另一个秘密
But I will say this:
他的背毛比任何
way more back hair than any guy
可以支付激光除毛的人都多
who can afford laser hair removal should have.
还有一次他们和一对兄妹上了床
And then there was the time they scored the brother/sister combo.
这是我们自从看唐尼和玛丽节目以来
It was everything we ever dreamed of
一直拥有的梦想
when watching Donnie and Marie.
她有点乡村气息 （这是唐尼和玛丽节目歌曲的歌词）
She was a little bit country.
他有点对黑人男人情有独钟
He was a little bit way into black guys.
巴尼和詹姆士在一起 组成了致命联合
Yeah, Barney and James together was a lethal combination.
因为两人的目标不同
Since there was never any crossover in targets,
所以詹姆士总是帮助巴尼
James was always there for Barney with the assist.
哇 你的围巾...
Whoa. Your scarf...
太有震撼力了!
it is fierce!
谢谢 H&M牌的 (瑞典顶级品牌H&M)
Thanks. H & M.
真的? 我可没看出来
What? I would never know,
因为它太热辣了 我的眼睛都要熔化了 我看不见了
'cause it is so hot that my eyes are melting. Oh, I can't see.
说到这里  你知道什么东西
Hey! You know, speaking of things
围着你会让你看起来更加美丽?
that would look good wrapped around you,
你认识我不是 同性恋的兄弟巴尼?
have you met my straight brother, Barney?
他可是很出... 等一下...色的 哦!
Oh, he is fab-- don't you go nowhere-- "ulous." Okay?
巴尼总是还詹姆士这个人情
And  Barney always returned the favor.
救命啊 他停止呼吸了
Help, I don't think he's breathing.
有人会人工呼吸吗?
Does anyone know mouth-to-mouth?
哦   天啊!我会!
Oh, my God, I do!
呃   好 换你来怎么样?
Okay, great. How 'bout you instead?
你能来我真是太高兴了!
Oh, man, I am so excited that you're here!
我已经很久没有和
It has been forever since I have been around anyone
任何玩得开的人一起玩了
even remotely fun.
我这么说是想伤你们的感情
Uh, yes offense.
今晚你们和我俩一起出去玩 是不?
You guys are still going out with us tonight, right?
- 不去 - 詹姆士
- No. - Jammies.
今晚? 已经九点多了...
Tonight? It's after 9:00 and...
而且我刚喝完热呼呼的汤
I have warm soup belly.
不...不...伙计们...
Oh, no, no, no, no, no. Guys...
你们都是年轻有魅力的人
you are young, attractive people here
在地球上这个最伟大的城市
in the greatest city on earth.
而在那个没人 爱搭理的怀俄明州里的
There are boys and girls
男男女女做梦都想到这个城市
in Nobody Cares, Wyoming, wishing they could be here.
但是他们只能在租来的 地下室里喝烂酒
But instead, they are in someone's basement drinking bad malt liquor,
考虑这个周六晚上是
debating whether or not they're going to spend their Saturday night
在商店的停车厂
in the parking lot of the feed store
还是在某个家伙的地下室里度过
or in some other dude's basement.
就冲这个  你们应该站起来
You owe it to them to rise up
扭着你们的懒屁股 穿上火辣的衣服
and shimmy your lazy asses into something hot,
然后出去实现他们的梦想!
and  you go out there and you live their dream!
- 跟我说"嘿 耶!" - 嘿 耶!
- Can I get a "hell, yeah"? - Hell, yeah!
- 跟我说"喔-喔!" - 喔-喔!
- Can I get a "woo-woo"? - Woo-woo!
我们为了怀俄明州 而狂欢吧! 走吧!
Go do it for Wyoming! Yes!
上帝在此见证!
Testify!
那晚 巴尼的愿望实现了
So that night, Barney got his wish.
我们都出门狂欢了
We all went out.
老爸我回来了!
Daddy's home!
噎!
Yeah.
怎么样  兄弟  你看上哪位了?
All right, bro. What do you like?
那个穿着超级紧身黑色T恤的人如何?
Guy in super tight black T?
肌肉黑男?
Super tight black guy?
长的和T先生一样的家伙?
Guy who looks like Mr. T?
第一位可以  第二位可以  第三位嘛... 喝完两杯马提尼后再问我
Mmm, yes, yes, and... talk to me after two martinis.
咱们再帮你看看 我的兄弟
Let's focus on you, my man.
我今天有点懒
I'm feeling lazy.
那个在喝巧克力鸡尾酒的女孩怎么样?
How 'bout girl with the chocolatini?
背后有纹身
Oh... boom, back tattoo.
用英雄救美方案?
Hero and the pig?
- 咱们上 - 开演
- Let's ride. - Fo' 'sho.
哎呀  宝贝  好漂亮的风骚章!
Damn baby, nice tramp stamp!
- 滚开 你这个死流氓! - 喂! 喂!
- Get off me, you pig! - Hey! Hey!
她的纹身不是用来邀请别人来摸她的
Her body art is not an invitation to grope her,
而是来表达她的内涵的
it's an expression of her inner self.
我相信她的内心世界 确实就像一个花丛中的海豚 (纹身图案)
I'm sure, in many ways, she is the dolphin encircled by flowers.
- 干什么? 干什么? - 怎么? 怎么?
- What? What? - What? What?
算了
Cool.
下次他再烦你 你就告诉我
Let me know if he bothers you again.
谢谢 你应该留下...以防万一
Thanks. You should stay close... just in case.
如果能让你觉得更放心的话
Sure. If it'll make you feel safer.
我叫巴尼
I'm Barney.
孩子们 在一个嘈杂拥挤的酒吧里
Now, kids, when you're out at a noisy, crowded bar,
很容易就能分辨出单身一族
you can always tell the difference between the singles
和情侣之间的区别
and the couples.
只要找到几个特征就行了
You just have to look for the signs.
- 分别行动! - 火辣的目标
- Break. - Boiling hot.
单身一族总是站着 为的是行动方便点
Singles stay on their feet for maneuverability.
- 嘿 - 嗨 你好吗?
- Hey! - Hi, how are ya?
你认识我兄弟?
Have you met my brother?
你好 来喝一杯
Oh, hello. Have a drink.
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet ya.
而情侣呢 光是走出家门 就已经让他们精疲力尽了
Couples, exhausted by the sheer act of leaving the house,
一到酒吧就 一个劲儿地找位子坐
are obsessed with finding a place to sit down.
还有许多其他的特征
There are a lot of other indicators, too.
比如说  酒精的选择
From choice of social lubricant...
还有基本的身体语言
...to basic body language.
总言而知  有很多方法可以来判断
But the point is, there are many ways to tell
一个人属于精神抖擞的单身一族
whether someone has Single Stamina
还是昏迷不醒的情侣一派
or Couples Coma.
我因该穿运动鞋来
I wish I would've worn sneakers.
我刚从一个 又胖毛又多的家伙那逃出来
I just got finished running from some fat, hairy guy
他的小弟弟想从他的皮裤子里 钻出来和我打招呼
who was periscoping out of his pleather pants.
门儿都没有!
Permission to come aboard denied.
我想念我的睡衣
I miss my jammies.
我不相信我竟然穿上了胸罩
I can't believe I wore a bra for this.
胸罩烦死人了 裹得紧紧的  太不自然了
Bras suck. They're so confining and unnatural.
里面挤得就像一个动物园
Yeah, they're like a boobie zoo.
那你就把胸罩脱掉吧 让里面的小崽崽轻松一下
Well, why don't you take it off then and let those puppies breathe?
别费力气了  你还是把口水 流在别的女人身上吧!
Oh, please go sweat on someone else.
可怜的家伙
Poor guy.
可怜的家伙?我的乳房更可怜
Poor guy? Poor my boobs.
一个男人要鼓足很大的勇气 去接近一个女孩子
Well, it takes a lot of guts to approach a girl
而你却中伤了他
and you just crushed him.
是的  是的 他看起来很受打击
Oh, yeah, yeah. He looks all broken up inside.
你们男人永远无法体会一个女孩
Whatever, you guys have no idea what it's like
被别人死缠烂打地 追着的感觉是什么样
to be on the receiving end.
我好可怜 我是个漂亮的女孩
"Oh, poor me. I'm a pretty girl
大家都想给我买酒
and everybody everywhere wants to buy me drinks
然后和我上床
and have sex with me."
哇
Waa.
我好可怜 我可以喝 粉红色的   美味的
"Oh, poor me. I get to order yummy, pink drinks
上面带大块果粒的
with chunks of real fruit that guys secretly like,
男生都暗地想喝却又怕 被嘲笑而不敢喝的鸡尾酒
but can't order because they'll be made fun of."
- 老兄 - 好喝极了
-  Dude. - They're delicious!
打扰以下  和我来喝一杯?
Excuse me. Join me in a shot?
不了  我已经喝的够多的了
Oh, no thanks. I've had enough.
他太注重身材了
He's too in shape,
跟他约会的话 一晚上都会谈论身体脂肪含量的
we'd spend all night talking about his body fat content.
失陪片刻
Now, if you'll excuse me,
我要去喝一杯 美味的上面带大块果粒的饮料...
I'm gonna go have a yummy, pink drink with fruit in it...
因为我是同性恋 所以没有人会笑话我
because I can.
你们知道吗 这是詹姆斯今天晚上
You know, that was, like, the third hot guy
拒绝的第三个帅哥
that James blew off tonight.
对啊  他不喝别人喝酒 还打呵欠
Yeah, he's turning down shots, he's yawning,
还抱怨脚疼
he's whining about his feet.
他和我们一样糟糕
He's as bad as we are.
是这么回事
He is.
等等 他和我们一模一样 你们觉得詹姆士...
Wait, he's exactly as bad as we are. You guys don't think that James is...
是不是有了男朋友?
in a relationship?
不 这不可能 他跟巴尼一样花心
No. There's no way. He's Barney's brother.
快看
Look at that.
他在发短信!
He's texting!
我的天啊!
Oh, my God!
他在热恋中
He is in a couple.
这会让巴尼疯掉的
This is gonna kill Barney.
什么事会让我疯掉?
What's gonna kill me?
到底怎么了?
What's going on?
巴...巴尼?
B-Barney?
你有没有注意到... 詹姆士有些不同寻常?
Have you noticed anything... different about James?
没有
No.
他刚做过美容  所以容光焕发
I mean, he's glowing from his peel, if that's what you mean.
我们有理由相信詹姆士正在...
We have reason to believe that James is, uh,
向你隐瞒着一些东西
maybe hiding something from you.
我知道你也许不喜欢听这些 但是...
I-I know you're not gonna like hearing this, but...
巴尼...
Barney...
你的兄弟现在...
your brother is...
变得专一了
monogamous.
这太荒谬了!
That's ridiculous!
就算他今天有点死气沉沉的
Just because he's a little sleepy,
没有和别人在厕所的小隔间里做爱!
and he hasn't had sex with anyone in a bathroom stall...
他没有和别人在厕所的小隔间里做爱?
He hasn't had sex with anyone in a bathroom stall.
巴尼...
And, Barney...
我并不想告诉你这个 但是...
I hate to be the one to tell you this, but...
他在发短信
he's texting.
不...他...不!
No, he... No!
这... 不可能
That... is impossible.
借过... 借过... 借过...
Excuse... Excuse... Ex...
嗨 兄弟
Hey, bro.
不要转移话题
Don't change the subject.
让我看看你的手机
Let me see your phone.
为什么?
Why?
我就是想看看 你的手机  让我看看
I just want to see your phone. Let me see your phone.
这只不过是部手机 有什么好看的?
No, it's just a phone. It's just a phone!
它有网络功能  还可以照像
And it's got Internet access, and it's got a camera on it,
你可以用它上网  干什么都行
and you can surf the Web and do the whole thing.
现在的高科技真是太惊人了
It's so amazing how far technology has come.
你的手机有什么功能?
What kind of phone do you have?
我有...
I got...
这是谁?
Who is this?
你的回答最好是 "我不记得这个人的名字"
And the answer better be: "I don't remember his name."
这是汤姆
That is Tom.
他是我的未婚夫
And he's my fianc?
嗨!
Hey.
我不支持
I don't support this.
你不支持同性恋结婚?
Gay marriage?
不光是同性恋结婚 我不支持结婚!
Not gay marriage-- marriage!
你怎么能这样做呢?
How can you do this?
我们是在同一个家庭里长大的 我们被灌输了同样的价值观
We were raised in the same house, with the same values!
相信我  我也挣扎了很久
Believe me, I fought this for a long time.
这种事情羞死人了
Come on, it's embarrassing.
开始的时候 这种事情对于我来说也很奇怪
Look, this felt unnatural to me, too, at first.
但是我坠入了爱河
But I fell in love.
我和汤姆意识到 我们不能和爱情作对
And Tom and I realized you can't fight love.
我的天啊
Oh, God.
你们俩就在一起做这个吗? 你们坐在家里
Is that what you two do together? You sit around the house
谈情说爱? 我想... 我马上就要呕出来了
and talk about love? I think... I'm gonna be sick.
好吧  好吧  听着
Okay, okay, look,
你要好好地考虑一下 好吗?
I need you to wrap your head around this, okay?
因为这件事已成定局
Because it is happening.
并且我希望你做我的伴郎
And I want you to be my best man.
什么? 没门
What? No way.
我很遗憾你是这么想的
Well, I'm sorry you feel that way.
我希望你能改变主意
I hope you change your mind.
两瓶啤酒 一杯shot (一种混合烈酒)
Two  beers, one shot.
简直就跟传染病一样
Oh, it's a freaking epidemic.
亲爱的!这个是给我作的?
Oh, sweetie! Did you make that for me?
是的
Yes.
龙虾大餐 史坦顿岛 谁去?
Clam Bake. Staten Island. Who's in?
算了 已经猜到你们不会去
Okay, I didn't have high hopes for that one.
好吧 这是我的问题
Okay, here's my thing.
如果同性恋开始结婚
If gay guys start getting married,
那全世界的人都会想结婚
then suddenly the whole world's gonna be doing it.
这就是他们的影响 他们起头
That's how it works. They start something,
然后6个月以后人们都跟着做
then six months later, everyone follows.
就像现在每个人都开始护理指甲
Like now everyone gets manicures.
我不护理指甲
I don't get manicures.
好吧  比如说... 比如说...去胸毛
Okay, then like how... Like getting your chest waxed.
你去胸毛?
You get your chest waxed?
我只是打个比方!
You know what I mean!
同性恋婚姻会让单身
Gay marriage is going to cause single life,
这种生活方式灭亡的
as we know it, to die out.
而美国家庭关系会因此而牢固不少
Think of how the American family will be strengthened.
我知道你很生气 但是你应该接受事实
Barney, I'm sorry you're upset, but you got to suck it up
要像一个男人一样来对待这个事情
and be a man about this.
不
No.
一直都是我和他一起疯狂玩乐
It's always been me and him together, being awesome,
当你们成双结对
while the rest of you walked two-by-two
走入没有性生活的无聊二人世界
onto your ark of sexless boredom.
即使詹姆士要结婚了
Just because James is getting married
这并不意味着将有什么变化
doesn't mean things are going to change.
好像你们从未发生过变化
Yeah. Like things haven't changed with you people.
我妹妹和一个 我不喜欢的家伙结婚了
Look, my sister married a guy I didn't like.
凉鞋配短袜  有没有搞错?
Sandals and socks-- come on, buddy.
但是我还是 带她出去为她庆祝
But I took her out, we celebrated.
应为那是我应该做的事情
It was the right thing to do.
你应该支持詹姆斯
You got to support him.
你说的对  泰德
You're right, Ted.
这正好是庆祝的理由
This is a cause for celebration.
我们应该带他出去好好地庆祝一下
We need to take him out and celebrate the commitment
他和汤姆即将走进婚姻的殿堂
he and Tom are about to make.
啊...这就是
Yeah. This is where we're celebrating
庆祝我和汤姆走进婚姻殿堂的地方?
the commitment that Tom and I are about to make?
什么?对呀!
What? Yeah!
那个笼子象征着婚姻
See, that cage represents your commitment.
我的天啊 自由的味道从来没有这么甜美过
Oh, my God. Freedom has never tasted so delicious.
Hey.
你经常健身?
You work out?
是的
I do.
你竟然注意到了!
And thank you for noticing.
你的体格也很健壮
You're obviously in very good shape yourself.
是的  我一直在努力健身
Well, I try.
那么你想跳支舞吗?
So you want to dance?
你知道吗? 你邀请我 我很开心
You know what? I'm very flattered, and, objectively,
你很有吸引力 但是这是我的未婚妻
you're a very attractive man, but this is actually my fiance.
对不起  其实我是 看见你在喝这种饮料所以我...
I'm sorry. You know, I saw your drink and I...
不 不 这个饮料不是我的 是她的...
No, no, this isn't my drink. This is hers.
不  这才是我的
No, it isn't.
随便怎么样吧
Whatever.
你呢?
How 'bout you?
我也是个异性恋者
Oh, I'm straight, too.
但是谢谢你在 我身上浪费的时间
But I thank you for your time,
谢谢你对我的身体感兴趣
and I appreciate your interest in my body.
你们看到了没?
You see that?
有人搭讪并不像你们说的那么糟糕
Being hit on doesn't have to be terrible.
而且对方离开的时候 都没有受到伤害
I feel flattered, and everyone left with their dignity.
我很喜欢你的毛衣
Hey, I really like your sweater.
你真的喜欢?
Wow. You actually do, don't you?
你不是想看 我的胸部或别的什么
You're not checking out my boobs or anything.
我的名字叫Gay・肯 你觉得呢?
My name's Gay Ken, what do you think?
我爱这个地方! 我们一起来跳舞!
I love this place! Let's dance!
- 而且不会被骚扰! - 谢谢
- And not be groped! - Whoo! Thank you.
- 好热辣! - 谢谢你!
- Damn. - Thank you!
- 我们太抢手了 - 毫无疑问!
- We're hot. - Totally.
然后汤姆对那个商人说
And then Tom says to the dealer
这个乔治亚手制时钟表有些小瑕疵
that the handmade Georgian clock has a chip on the corner.
就这样我们 以半价买了下来  你猜怎么?!
Blam, we get that puppy half price. What up?!
其实我们骗他的!
Bam!
看来你们在手工艺展览会上淘到宝了
Sounds like you really rocked that arts and crafts fair.
Oh, yeah, oh, yeah.
能和你讲这些事情
Hey, oh, my God. This is so liberating,
我心里感觉舒坦了许多
being able to talk about this to you.
我真是迫不及待地想 介绍汤姆给你认识
I cannot wait for you to meet Tom.
我也迫不及待地 想介绍我的朋友...
And I cannot wait for you to meet my good friend...
就是他
this guy.
打扰一下  你知道谁愿意
Excuse me, do you know anyone who would like to buy
和我强壮的 幽默的 慷慨的兄弟喝上一杯?
my incredibly muscular, fun, large-handed brother a drink?
哎哎哎!今天你是主角 巴尼
Eh, eh, eh, let's focus on you, Barnaby. Okay.
我注意到一群女人因为在同性恋酒舞厅
All right. I spy a group of women who have let their defenses down
而卸下了防卫
because they are in a gay club.
你看到那边那个小妞了?
You see that chick right there?
她看起来会喜欢 运动代理商或者踢足球的男人
She looks like she'd fall for sports agent and football player.
好的  我去试试
Okay, I'm in.
这次我是当英雄还是流氓?
Which one am I?
拜托
Please.
他很害羞 喜欢网球和巴西 而且...
He's very shy, loves tennis and Brazil, and drops his pants
三杯马提尼酒后就是你的人了 快上吧!  伙计  快点!
after three dirty martinis. Now go, man, go!
我从来没有 想到过巴尼也会这么脆弱
I just never thought I'd see Barney so vulnerable.
我想没有人喜欢孤零零地 一个人度过一生的感觉
Well, I guess no one wants to feel like they're going through the world alone.
看我夹在一个美味的三明治的中间!
Look at me, in a yummy sandwich!
我们现在正忙着呢 所以...
Okay, we're actually right in the middle of something right now, so...
那我也和你们一起"忙"吧!怎么样?
Ooh, I know what I want to be in the middle of. Thoughts?
难道两个异性恋男人就不能 来同性恋酒吧?
God, can't two straight guys come to a gay dance club,
听听音乐  讨论些问题 而不被人打扰?
enjoy some techno and good conversation without being bothered?
怎么样?还是在 享受被男人追捧的感觉?
How's it going, guys? Still enjoying the attentions of men?
刚才那人是在十分钟内 第八个跟我们搭讪的
That's like the eighth guy who's hit on us in ten minutes.
傻小子一直对 我的裤子含情脉脉
It's  like, hello, my eyes are up here.
而且来的都不是帅哥
And it's never the hot ones.
都是些没人要的家伙 真扫兴!
It's always the losers. Bums me out!
看起来他们有所领悟
Looks like the boys learned their lesson.
你是不是很希望有人跟你搭讪?
Do you totally miss being hit on?
对啊! 我们去找个体育酒吧 (体育酒吧里一般都是异性恋男人）
Oh, totally. Let's go find a sports bar.
詹姆士  你喜欢手工艺不是吗?
James, James, since you like arts and crafts,
看看查尔斯用樱桃枝打出的蝴蝶结
look at what Charles here made with cherry stems.
他是用舌头做的
He did it with his tongue.
没错
Yeah.
巴尼
Barney.
把你的号码输进我兄弟的手机里
So, Charles, why don't you put your number in my brother's phone,
等他心情好点的时候...
and once he's in a funner mood...
巴尼 我不想要他的号码
Barney, Barney, I don't want his number.
谁的号码我都不要 听见了吗?
I don't want anyone's number, okay?
我就要结婚了
I'm getting married.
Wow.
- 祝你们好运 - 谢谢
- Best of luck to you both. - Thank you.
我的号码留里面了
My number's in here.
我是一个非常谨慎的人
I'm very discreet.
好吧  好吧   打扰一下
Okay, okay, excuse me.
巴尼  家庭会议
Barney, family talk.
兄弟  你不要这么做了好不好?
Okay, dude, you have got to stop this, okay?
我知道我要结婚的 这个事实对你的生活方式产生了威胁
I know that my getting married is threatening to your way of life...
哦?这只是我的生活方式?
Oh, so now it's my way of life?
我以为这是我们共同的生活方式
I thought it was our way of life.
你完全了背弃了我们的生活方式
You've completely turned your back on it.
看看你  你甚至没有穿西装
Look at you, not even suited up.
你还记得我们 为什么而穿西装吗  詹姆士?
Do you remember why we suit up, James?
泡马子
To get laid.
是为了让别人知道我们与众不同
To show people that we are different
为了和数以百万 穿着T恤衫和牛仔的小子区别开来
from the millions of T-shirt and jeans lemmings out there.
西装证明我们不可蔑视的力量
The suit shows that we are a force to be reckoned with,
我们是两个人的军队 有自己的准则
a two-person army that plays by its own rules.
但是你脱下了制服 你投靠了敌人
But you've taken off the uniform, you've crossed enemy lines,
而且你抛弃了我
and you've abandoned me.
我是不会让你这样做的
Well, I'm not gonna let you do that.
现在摆脱你这场愚蠢的婚姻还不迟!
It's not too late to back out of this stupid marriage thing!
你不需结婚 兄弟!
You don't have to do this, bro!
- 我需要 - 为什么?!
- Yes, I do. - Why?!
因为汤姆和我想要一个孩子
Because Tom and I are gonna have a baby.
什么? 会有一个孩子?
What? There's gonna be a baby?
是的  我们打算收养一个孩子
Yes. We're adopting.
天啊  我要当叔叔了?
Oh, my God. I'm gonna be an uncle?
你一辈子都会是
For the rest of your life.
这就是巴尼怎么变成了巴尼叔叔
And that's how Barney became Uncle Barney.
一年以后  在詹姆士的婚礼上
A year later, at James's wedding,
这天是巴尼最自豪的一天
Barney could not have been more proud.
向詹姆士和汤姆致敬
To James and Tom.
希望你们新婚快乐长命百岁
May you have a long and happy life together.
并且希望我的皮肤和性欲 永远都会像年轻小伙一样好
And may I always have the skin and libido of a much younger man.
- 干杯 - 干杯
- Cheers. - Cheers.
讲的不错
Nice one.
谢谢  我决定不去讲 詹姆斯大学时代是个异性恋
Thanks. I decided to leave out the hetero college phase.
没有人想听这个
No one wants to hear about that.
你的演讲完美极了
It was perfect.
汤姆的爸爸甚至都感动得搞哭了
You even made Tom's dad cry.
或者也许是因为他是共和党人所以被气哭的 (美国共和党不支持同性恋婚姻)
Might have been doing that because he's a Republican.
哇!
Whoa.
都九点了
It's 9:00.
我们该回去了 你们要搭个顺风车?
We should be getting back. You guys want to split a cab?
不了  我想再多呆会
Uh, no, I think I'm gonna stay a little bit longer.
我也是  我还不太累
Yeah, me, too. I'm not tired at all.
时间很晚了 我要带老婆回家了
All right, well, it's getting late. Got to get the wife home.
不要那么叫我 听起来好像我很胖
Oh, stop calling me that. It makes me sound fat.
简直就跟传染病一样
Ugh, it's a freaking epidemic.
- 我可以来看看小家伙? - 当然
- May I? - Yeah.
小家伙
Hey, buddy.
你的父母结婚了
Your parents are married.
你好好听我说
Now, listen, you.
不要因为你被已婚父母抚养
Just because you're being raised by married people
而选择他们的生活方式
doesn't mean you have to choose that lifestyle.
来　支持一下
High-five.
幸运的是 你有我
Luckily, you got me.
20年零六个月以后你就21岁了
In 20 and a half years, you'll be 21,
到那时我就...
and I will be...
我还没有决定那时候我多大岁数
Well, I haven't decided how old I'll be yet.
但是我们将是称兄道弟的侄子和叔叔
But we are gonna bro out, uncle and nephew style.
你要跟着我
Stick with me, kid.
我来教你怎么生活
I am gonna teach you how to live.
顺便说一下  好挺的西装
Great suit, by the way.
谁最可爱?
Who is the cutest?
我真搞不懂
I don't get it.
十年级的时候 汤姆还喜欢我的大胸
Tom liked my breasts in tenth grade.
为什么他现在不喜欢了呢?
Why doesn't he like them now?
为什么?
Why?
罗莎  为什么总想得到 那些不可能得到的东西呢?
Rosa, why always be attracted to the unavailable ones?
为什么不接受 你很美丽的这个事实
Why not accept the fact that you're a beautiful woman
你是个值得别人去爱的女人
who is worthy of love?
我说这些你能勇敢地接受?
Are you brave enough to hear that?
你...
You...